<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Today I Learnt</title>
    <link>https://dineshba.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Today I Learnt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 22:45:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dineshba.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My OSS Journey</title>
      <link>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 22:45:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/oss/</guid>
      <description>I would love to quickly share my OSS Journey. I will keep it very short. I am writing this now (on September 2019), because I gonna celebrate my first anniversary of my OSS journey by this October.
   Before one year (October 2018) Now (September 2019)     No PRs to any tools/libs 31 PRS (25 Merged, 3 Open, 3 Closed) refer   Know at hight level what the tool is doing Know what internally it is happening (you might get to know which function is getting called :-P)   Okay to live with bugs Raise issue or fix the bug (refer)   Okay to live with existing feature Trying to think what feature is helpful for me (and for others also)   Not attached to any tool/lib Feeling proud about the tool/lib   People from different planet can only contribute No they are just like me   No tools by me Have atleast one tool (gg)   Nothing special about me My resume shines   No cool tshirts Have two tshirts (Hacktoberfest, TW Internal hacktoberfest)     Note: You have to be logged in github to see the above pr and issue links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme of my website</title>
      <link>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:50:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/theme/</guid>
      <description>Backbone of my website: I am using hugo to build this website. Thanks to Aswin Karthik for his blog by which I setup this website. Just write markdown files and push, and travis-ci will publish your website. So cool !!!.
There are lot of themes available here. After some search, I landed to current theme which is hyde. I really liked the theme and it saved lot of my time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I am using fzf for every 5 min of my programming life</title>
      <link>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/fzf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:41:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/fzf/</guid>
      <description>Installation for new users $ brew install fzf $ $(brew --prefix)/opt/fzf/install # useful key bindings and fuzzy completion   Note: Its better to use key bindings and fuzzy completion
 Default options that I use export FZF_DEFAULT_OPTS=&#39;--height 40% --reverse --border&#39;  My usages To Search in command history: CTRL + R
To Change directory: cd + (CTRL + T) # type cd and then press CTRL plus T or cd ** + TAB  To find and open files in vim(or any editor): vim $(fzf) vim + (CTRL + T) vim ** + TAB vim $(fzf --preview &#39;cat {}&#39;)   You can even search and open multiple files using tab</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super cool exec command</title>
      <link>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/exec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 22:56:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dineshba.github.io/posts/exec/</guid>
      <description>exec (built-in command) We can use exec for two use cases (as far as I learned today :-P)
To create independent shell from current shell Usual way:
$ bash # created a bash shell $ #do whatever you wanted $ exit # will go back to the shell which it created  Using exec:
$ exec bash #created a bash shell and killed the current shell $ #do whatever you wanted $ exit # will not go back to the shell which it created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://dineshba.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 20:05:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dineshba.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a coding freak who is always interested in solving/seeking challenging problems.
Being in Thoughtworks, I found a lot of opportunities to work in various domains, few of them being - devops tools(docker, kubernetes, terraform, etc), mobile(both iOS and Android), micro services architecture.
In all experiences on my projects, we have used a ton of open source tools and benefited a lot. After taking a lot from community I felt its only natural to give back as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>